#7: Bones
#7: 骨骼
In the previous lessons we have learned how to animate a simple character.
在前面的课程我们学习了如何动画简单的角色。
This technique is great for simple animations.
这技术非常适用于简单的动画。
But it also has drawbacks: it's not very comfortable to control the character's pose.
但缺点是：它不是很适于角色姿态控制。
Every time we have to select particular part and only then it can be moved.
每一次我们都不得不选择特定的部分，而且只有它可以移动。
Moreover, we have to think about creating correct group structure.
此外，我们不得不要全盘考虑创建正确的组的结构。
If our character is just a little bit more complex, then we'll have to create many nesting groups...
如果我们的角色稍微复杂一点，那么就不得不创建更多的嵌套的组...
...and it gets hard to manipulate them.
...这让操控变得困难起来。
For animation of characters and other complex structures you can use bones.
给角色和其他复杂的结构做动画，你可以采用骨骼。
With bones it's very easy to create a skeleton like this and control a character.
骨骼能轻而易举创建像这个控制角色的骨架。
Now I'm going to show you how to create such structure from scratch.
现在我要给你展示怎样从零创建这样的结构。
Open the "character-2" folder.
打开"character-2" 文件夹。
Here we have an image of a whole character...
我们这里有个完整的角色...
...and all its parts separated.
...还有分开的各个部分。
First let's import the whole image. That will be our reference.
我们先导入完整的图片。用来做参照物。
Next, add the separate parts.
接着，添加分开的部分。
Now group everything together and scale to fit the working area.
现在把所有都成组在一起缩小使之适合工作区大小。
Now it's time to clean up the mess. Let's separate all the parts.
现在我们要清理一下。分开各个部分。
For our convenience, let's make the image of the whole character semi-transparent.
为了方便，先把完整的角色变成半透明。
Layer transparency is defined by the "Amount" parameter. Let's set its value to 0.5.
层的透明度是由 "Amount" 参数定义的。把汁设为0.5。
Now let's put all parts into their places.
现在我们把各个部分都放到正确的地方。
Here goes the body... the head.
这是躯干... 头
Then the lower limbs - the thigh...
接着，腿 – 臀...
the leg...
大腿...
and the foot.
足。
The second leg appeared to be above the body but it's easy to fix.
第二条腿好像在躯体之上，很容易纠正的。
Just send it to the back.
只要把它放到后边去。
All remaining parts are assembled in the same way.
剩下的其他部分也用同样的方法组装起来
It's kind of fun, like a puzzle.
有点意思，像拼图。
And don't for get to save your work regularly.
不要忘了经常保存你的工作。
Done.
完成。
We don't need the reference layer any more, so it's better to hide it.
我们不再需要参照层，最好把它隐藏起来。
Now we can add a skeleton layer.
现在我们可以添加骨架层了。
Let's put it inside of the group, above all image layers.
把它放在这个组里，位于所有的图像层之上。
Expand the group, select its first layer...
展开组，选择第一个层。
right-click it and choose "New Layer" > "Other" > "Skeleton".
右键点击，选择"New Layer" > "Other" > "Skeleton".
So we have a skeleton layer created, with one bone.
我们的骨架层出来了，它带有一根骨头。
Here it is.
就是这个。
The green point is the bone origin.
绿色的点是骨头的原点。
The brown one determines its angle and length.
棕色的决定它的角度和长度。
Let's create one more bone.
再多创建一跟骨头。
Right-click at any point of the existing bone and choose "Create Child Bone".
右键点击现有的骨头的任意点然后选择"Create Child Bone".
And there the second bone appears.
第二根骨头出现了。
It's subordinate to the first bone.
它是第一跟骨头的从属。
Look, when I move the first one, the second one moves as well.
看，当我移动第一根骨头，第二根也会跟着移动。
But the second bone can move on it's own.
但第二根骨头自己也能动。
That's how the bone hierarchy works.
这是骨头的层次运作方式。
So, let's put the first bone into the right location.
好，把第一根骨头放到正确的位置。
It will be responsible for the position of the whole character.
它负责把控整个角色的位置。
The second bone is for the body. We put it here.
第二根骨头分配给躯体。我们把它放在这里。
Since arms and head should subordinate to the body...
因为手臂和头都是应该附属在躯干上...
...we'll create their bones from the body bone.
...我们从躯干骨骼上创建它们的骨头。
Right-click it and choose "Create Child Bone".
右键点击它并选择"Create Child Bone".
Now we create a bone for the lower part of the arm...
现在我们创建前臂的骨头...
...and from that bone create a child bone for the hand.
...再在其基础上创建用于控制手部的骨头。
Repeat the same procedure for the second arm.
对第二条手臂重复这个步骤。
The legs should stay still if the body bends, so make them belong to the first bone.
在躯干弯曲时腿应该保持不动的，所以让它们归属到第一根骨头上去。
Next, create a bone for the ankle and for the foot.
接着，创建一根用于脚踝和足的骨头。
In the same way create bones for the second leg.
用同样的方法创建第二条腿的骨头。
The skeleton is ready.
骨架准备好了。
Although just now it doesn't affect any character part and moves on its own.
不过现在它还不会影响角色的任何部分，只能自己移动。
What we need now is to link all the parts to the skeleton.
我们现在要做的是链接全部部件到骨架。
To connect the body, select both the body layer and the skeleton.
要了解躯干，选择躯体层和骨架。
Click the body, press Ctrl and click the skeleton in the layers list.
点击躯体，按下Ctrl点击层列表里的骨架。
Next left-click the green point of body layer.
接着左键点击躯干层的绿色点。
That way we indicate what exactly should be connected.
这样我们明确指示所要链接的部分。
Then right-click at any handle of bone and choose "Link to Bone".
然后右键点击骨骼的任一控制句柄并选择“链接到骨骼”。
Done! The body is linked now.
完成！躯干链接好了。
Let's connect all the remaining parts in the same way.
用同样的方法把其余的部分也联接起来。
If you have linked some part to a wrong bone, just link it to another one.
如果链接了错的骨骼上，只要再链接到另外一个上。
It will reconnect automatically.
就会自动重新联接。
The character is ready. Let's try to move him.
角色准备就绪。试着动动他。
Note, that when I'm dragging the tip of a bone, the bone is automatically stretching the image.
注意，当我拖拉骨骼的一端，骨骼会自动拉伸图像。
That's helps a lot in most cases.
这在多数情况下都是有用的。
But sometimes this effect is not desirable.
但是有时这个效果不是我们想要的。
The head is an example: we might want to bend it, but not to stretch.
头部就是一个明显的例子：我们可能要bend it，但不要拉伸它。
No problem, for this very specific case each bone has a blue point, here.
没问题，这种情形每一个骨骼都有一个蓝色点，这个位置。
It allows to change a bone angle without affecting its length. Like this.
它能改变一个骨骼的角度而不影响它的长度。像这样。
If layer is linked to a bone, that doesn't mean it should be controlled using the bone only.
即使层链接到了一个骨骼，也不是说它就只能通过骨骼来控制。
Nothing of the kind. We can still move it by itself.
用不着担心。我们还是可以通过它自身来移动的。
The only difference, that now it moves relatively to the bone it has been linked to.
唯一不同的是，现在是相对于链接的骨骼移动。
So transformations of the bone and layer are composed together.
骨骼和层的变换合到一起了。
Finally, one more important remark.
最后，还有一个重要的提示。
All parts of our character are located inside the group we've scaled-down in the beginning.
角色的所有部分都放在这个我们一开始就做过缩小的组里。
And the skeleton layer was placed inside of this group.
骨架层也是放在这个组里面。
It is crucial since both a skeleton and the parts we are linking to it must share the same coordinate system.
这点非常关键，因为骨架和与之链接的角色各个部分共用同一坐标系。
If we create a skeleton outside the group...
如果与其外创建骨架...
...the bones will have different coordinates comparing to the objects.
...各骨骼会有和物体不一致的坐标。
You might not notice this while linking...
在链接期间你可能会对此视而不见...
...but when you try to change a bone position, nasty things are sure to happen.
...但当你试图改变骨骼的位置，糟糕的事情就将出现无疑。
Let's save and close this file and I will show you an example about this.
我们保持并关闭这个文件，让我来向你示范一下这种情形。
Let's assemble a part of our character - just a body, head, and arm.
我们装配角色的一部分 - 躯干，头和手臂。
Suppose, we decided to assemble the arm like this: ...
假设，我们决定这样装配手臂：...
placed it here...
放在这里...
then grouped...
再成组...
...moved, and also turned.
...移动， and also turned.
As you understand, all the arm parts would be in the other coordinate system...
如你所了解的，手臂的所有部分都会在另外一个坐标系里...
... because we have transformed their parent group.
...因为我们已经变换了它的父辈组。
Let's try to attach everything to a skeleton.
让我们把所有都黏附到一个骨架上。
The body... head... and arm...
躯干... 头部... 还有手臂...
...all connected.
...全部都联结好了。
Now let's try to change the pose.
现在试试改变姿势。
As you can see, the head and body are fine, but the arms just go wild.
如你所见，头部和躯干很好，但是手臂乱套了。
That's all because of transformed group.
这全都归咎于变换的组。
If the group hasn't been transformed, then everything would be fine. It wouldn't  cause any troubles.
如果组没有被变换，那么一切安然。不会造成任何状况。
To fix the issue we can get parts out of the group...
要修复这个问题我们可以把这部分移出这个组...
...and re-align them to skeleton.
...并重新对其到骨架上。
But now we'll go another way.
不过我们要用另外一个方法。
Let's suppose we don't need our character to bend his wrist and elbow joints.
我们假设我们不需要角色弯曲手腕和肘关节。
So one bone for the whole arm would be enough and we can connect the whole group to it.
一根骨骼对应这条手臂就够了，我们可以把整个组联接给它。
Yes, you've got it right -
对，你完成了 -
... the groups also could be connected to a skeleton in the same way as image layers.
... 和图像层的方法一样，组也可以联接到骨架。
But I guess you already figured out that an image layer actually is also a group...
不过，我猜你已经知道每个图像层实质上就是一个组...
...or, to be more precise, a Switch Group.
...或者，更准确的说，是一个切换组(Switch)。
And the real image layer is located inside.
真正的图像层处于其内部。
But I digress.
我有点岔开话题了。
First, we have to disconnect the parts inside of this group from the skeleton.
首先，我们要取消这个组里的全部和骨架的联接。
Select the part you need...
选择需要的部分...
...find the Transformation parameter...
...找到变换（Transformation）参数...
...right-click it and choose "Disconnect".
...右键点击，选择“不联接(Disconnect)"。
Yes, this is the same way as we deleted parameter animation.
是的，这个和我们之前删除参数动画的方法是一样的。
Don't get surprised. ^__^
不用觉得奇怪^__^
Now let's link the group.
现在我们链接组。
Done.
完成。
Well, that's it. In the next lesson will try to create a walkcycle for our character.
好了，就到这里。下一节课，我们要创建角色的行走循环动画。